export const easyLevel = [
    {
        question: "What is the correct file extension for Python files?",
        option1: ".py",
        option2: ".python",
        option3: ".pyt",
        option4: ".pt",
        ans: ".py"
    },
    {
        question: "Which keyword is used to define a function in Python?",
        option1: "func",
        option2: "define",
        option3: "def",
        option4: "function",
        ans: "def"
    },
    {
        question: "How do you output text in Python?",
        option1: "print()",
        option2: "echo()",
        option3: "console.log()",
        option4: "printf()",
        ans: "print()"
    },
    {
        question: "Which data type is used to store a sequence of characters in Python?",
        option1: "char",
        option2: "string",
        option3: "str",
        option4: "text",
        ans: "str"
    },
    {
        question: "How do you create a single-line comment in Python?",
        option1: "// This is a comment",
        option2: "/* This is a comment */",
        option3: "# This is a comment",
        option4: "-- This is a comment",
        ans: "# This is a comment"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a valid variable name in Python?",
        option1: "my_variable",
        option2: "1st_variable",
        option3: "_myVariable",
        option4: "myVariable123",
        ans: "1st_variable"
    },
    {
        question: "Which operator is used for exponentiation in Python?",
        option1: "^",
        option2: "**",
        option3: "//",
        option4: "exp()",
        ans: "**"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `print(5 // 2)` output?",
        option1: "2.5",
        option2: "2",
        option3: "3",
        option4: "2.0",
        ans: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a valid data type in Python?",
        option1: "int",
        option2: "float",
        option3: "real",
        option4: "tuple",
        ans: "real"
    },
    {
        question: "How do you get the length of a list in Python?",
        option1: "size(my_list)",
        option2: "my_list.length()",
        option3: "len(my_list)",
        option4: "count(my_list)",
        ans: "len(my_list)"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `print(type(10))` output?",
        option1: "<class 'int'>",
        option2: "<class 'float'>",
        option3: "<class 'double'>",
        option4: "<class 'number'>",
        ans: "<class 'int'>"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is used to take input from a user in Python?",
        option1: "input()",
        option2: "get_input()",
        option3: "scan()",
        option4: "read()",
        ans: "input()"
    },
    {
        question: "How do you check if two values are equal in Python?",
        option1: "=",
        option2: "==",
        option3: "===",
        option4: "<=>",
        ans: "=="
    },
    {
        question: "Which function is used to convert a string into an integer?",
        option1: "float()",
        option2: "toInt()",
        option3: "str()",
        option4: "int()",
        ans: "int()"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `bool([])` return?",
        option1: "True",
        option2: "False",
        option3: "None",
        option4: "Error",
        ans: "False"
    },
    {
        question: "Which statement is used to exit a loop in Python?",
        option1: "exit",
        option2: "break",
        option3: "return",
        option4: "stop",
        ans: "break"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `range(5)` produce?",
        option1: "[1, 2, 3, 4, 5]",
        option2: "[0, 1, 2, 3, 4]",
        option3: "[0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5]",
        option4: "(0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5)",
        ans: "[0, 1, 2, 3, 4]"
    },
    {
        question: "How do you open a file in Python for reading?",
        option1: "open('file.txt', 'r')",
        option2: "open('file.txt', 'read')",
        option3: "open('file.txt', 'w')",
        option4: "open('file.txt', 'rb')",
        ans: "open('file.txt', 'r')"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a mutable data type in Python?",
        option1: "tuple",
        option2: "string",
        option3: "list",
        option4: "int",
        ans: "list"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `print('Hello' * 3)` output?",
        option1: "HelloHelloHello",
        option2: "Hello 3 times",
        option3: "Error",
        option4: "HelloHello Hello",
        ans: "HelloHelloHello"
    }
];

export const mediumLevel = [
    {
        question: "What will `print(bool('False'))` output?",
        option1: "False",
        option2: "True",
        option3: "None",
        option4: "Error",
        ans: "True"
    },
    {
        question: "What does `list.append(5)` do in Python?",
        option1: "Adds 5 at the beginning of the list",
        option2: "Adds 5 at the end of the list",
        option3: "Replaces the first element with 5",
        option4: "Inserts 5 at the middle of the list",
        ans: "Adds 5 at the end of the list"
    },
    {
        question: "Which method is used to remove an item from a dictionary in Python?",
        option1: "remove()",
        option2: "del()",
        option3: "discard()",
        option4: "pop()",
        ans: "pop()"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `my_list = [1, 2, 3]; my_list[1:2] = [4, 5]` change `my_list` to?",
        option1: "[1, 4, 5, 3]",
        option2: "[1, 2, 4, 5, 3]",
        option3: "[1, 4, 3]",
        option4: "[1, 5, 3]",
        ans: "[1, 4, 5, 3]"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `print(2 and 3)` output?",
        option1: "True",
        option2: "False",
        option3: "2",
        option4: "3",
        ans: "3"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following statements correctly creates a set in Python?",
        option1: "my_set = {}",
        option2: "my_set = []",
        option3: "my_set = set()",
        option4: "my_set = set([])",
        ans: "my_set = set()"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `print(sorted([3, 1, 4, 1, 5, 9], reverse=True))` output?",
        option1: "[9, 5, 4, 3, 1, 1]",
        option2: "[1, 1, 3, 4, 5, 9]",
        option3: "[9, 4, 5, 1, 1, 3]",
        option4: "[1, 3, 4, 5, 9, 1]",
        ans: "[9, 5, 4, 3, 1, 1]"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is used to get both index and value while iterating a list?",
        option1: "for i in list",
        option2: "enumerate()",
        option3: "range(len(list))",
        option4: "list.index()",
        ans: "enumerate()"
    },
    {
        question: "What does `list(set([1, 2, 2, 3, 4, 4]))` return?",
        option1: "[1, 2, 2, 3, 4, 4]",
        option2: "[1, 2, 3, 4]",
        option3: "[4, 3, 2, 1]",
        option4: "[1, 1, 2, 3, 4]",
        ans: "[1, 2, 3, 4]"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the output of `print(3 * 'abc')`?",
        option1: "abcabcabc",
        option2: "abc abc abc",
        option3: "3abc",
        option4: "abc*3",
        ans: "abcabcabc"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the correct way to define a class in Python?",
        option1: "class Car {}",
        option2: "def class Car:",
        option3: "class Car:",
        option4: "Car class:",
        ans: "class Car:"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the correct syntax to open a file named `data.txt` for writing?",
        option1: "open('data.txt', 'w')",
        option2: "open('data.txt', 'r')",
        option3: "open('data.txt', 'a')",
        option4: "open('data.txt', 'wb')",
        ans: "open('data.txt', 'w')"
    },
    {
        question: "How do you check if a key exists in a dictionary?",
        option1: "dict.has_key(key)",
        option2: "key in dict",
        option3: "dict.contains(key)",
        option4: "key.exists(dict)",
        ans: "key in dict"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following correctly implements a generator function?",
        option1: "def func(): return 1",
        option2: "def func(): yield 1",
        option3: "def func(): yield return 1",
        option4: "def func(): generator 1",
        ans: "def func(): yield 1"
    },
    {
        question: "What does the `zip()` function do?",
        option1: "Joins two strings",
        option2: "Combines two lists element-wise",
        option3: "Merges two dictionaries",
        option4: "Sorts a list in ascending order",
        ans: "Combines two lists element-wise"
    }
];

export const hardLevel = [
    {
        question: "What will be the output of `print(2**(3**2), (2**3)**2)`?",
        option1: "512 512",
        option2: "512 64",
        option3: "64 64",
        option4: "Error",
        ans: "512 64"
    },
    {
        question: "What does the expression `list(filter(lambda x: x % 2, range(10)))` return?",
        option1: "[0, 2, 4, 6, 8]",
        option2: "[1, 3, 5, 7, 9]",
        option3: "[2, 4, 6, 8]",
        option4: "[1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9]",
        ans: "[1, 3, 5, 7, 9]"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a valid way to define a Python lambda function?",
        option1: "lambda x: x + 2",
        option2: "lambda x, y: x * y",
        option3: "lambda x: return x + 2",
        option4: "lambda x: (x**2)",
        ans: "lambda x: return x + 2"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the output of `print(sum(map(lambda x: x*x, range(1, 6))))`?",
        option1: "55",
        option2: "15",
        option3: "30",
        option4: "None",
        ans: "55"
    },
    {
        question: "Which module provides support for multi-threading in Python?",
        option1: "threading",
        option2: "multiprocessing",
        option3: "asyncio",
        option4: "subprocess",
        ans: "threading"
    },
    {
        question: "Which statement about Python generators is true?",
        option1: "Generators use `yield` instead of `return`",
        option2: "Generators can only return one value",
        option3: "Generators are slower than regular functions",
        option4: "Generators cannot be used inside loops",
        ans: "Generators use `yield` instead of `return`"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following will raise an error?",
        option1: "a = {1, 2, 3}",
        option2: "b = {}",
        option3: "c = set()",
        option4: "d = {1, 2, 3, [4, 5]}",
        ans: "d = {1, 2, 3, [4, 5]}"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the output of `print((lambda x: x**3)(3))`?",
        option1: "9",
        option2: "27",
        option3: "81",
        option4: "Error",
        ans: "27"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following correctly implements a decorator?",
        option1: "`@decorator_function def my_func(): pass`",
        option2: "`@decorator my_func(): pass`",
        option3: "`decorator_function(my_func)`",
        option4: "`def decorator_function(): return my_func`",
        ans: "@decorator_function def my_func(): pass"
    },
    {
        question: "What will be the output of `print(3 < 4 < 5)`?",
        option1: "True",
        option2: "False",
        option3: "Syntax Error",
        option4: "None",
        ans: "True"
    },
    {
        question: "What does `itertools.permutations(['A', 'B', 'C'])` return?",
        option1: "All possible pairs of elements",
        option2: "All possible orders of elements",
        option3: "Combinations of elements",
        option4: "None of the above",
        ans: "All possible orders of elements"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `print({1, 2, 3}.issubset({1, 2, 3, 4}))` return?",
        option1: "True",
        option2: "False",
        option3: "Error",
        option4: "None",
        ans: "True"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the output of `print({i: i*i for i in range(3)})`?",
        option1: "{0: 0, 1: 1, 2: 4}",
        option2: "{0: 1, 1: 2, 2: 3}",
        option3: "{0: 0, 1: 2, 2: 4}",
        option4: "Error",
        ans: "{0: 0, 1: 1, 2: 4}"
    },
    {
        question: "Which method is used to make an object callable like a function?",
        option1: "__call__()",
        option2: "__str__()",
        option3: "__repr__()",
        option4: "__getattr__()",
        ans: "__call__()"
    },
    {
        question: "What does `print({1, 2, 3}.intersection({3, 4, 5}))` return?",
        option1: "{1, 2}",
        option2: "{3}",
        option3: "{3, 4, 5}",
        option4: "Error",
        ans: "{3}"
    },
    {
        question: "What does `collections.Counter(['a', 'b', 'b', 'c', 'c', 'c'])` return?",
        option1: "{'a': 1, 'b': 2, 'c': 3}",
        option2: "{'a': 2, 'b': 2, 'c': 3}",
        option3: "{'a': 1, 'b': 1, 'c': 1}",
        option4: "None of the above",
        ans: "{'a': 1, 'b': 2, 'c': 3}"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the output of `''.join(sorted('hello', reverse=True))`?",
        option1: "'ehllo'",
        option2: "'ollhe'",
        option3: "'ollhe'",
        option4: "'olleh'",
        ans: "'ollhe'"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is an immutable data type?",
        option1: "List",
        option2: "Set",
        option3: "Tuple",
        option4: "Dictionary",
        ans: "Tuple"
    },
    {
        question: "Which module is used for working with regular expressions?",
        option1: "os",
        option2: "sys",
        option3: "re",
        option4: "regex",
        ans: "re"
    },
    {
        question: "What will be the output of `print(1 == True and 0 == False)`?",
        option1: "True",
        option2: "False",
        option3: "Syntax Error",
        option4: "None",
        ans: "True"
    },
    {
        question: "Which keyword is used for handling exceptions?",
        option1: "handle",
        option2: "catch",
        option3: "try",
        option4: "except",
        ans: "except"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following functions is used for deep copying an object?",
        option1: "copy.copy()",
        option2: "copy.deepcopy()",
        option3: "copy.clone()",
        option4: "copy.duplicate()",
        ans: "copy.deepcopy()"
    },
    {
        question: "What will `print(2 < 3 == 3 > 1)` return?",
        option1: "True",
        option2: "False",
        option3: "Syntax Error",
        option4: "None",
        ans: "True"
    }
];

export const python = [easyLevel, mediumLevel, hardLevel];
